

Adel Ferdjoukh

Software Tech Lead



29 years



Toulouse, France



+33 695 55 89 13



www.adel-ferdjoukh.ovh



ferdjoukh@gmail.com

About me ———

PhD. in computer science (software engineering). Worked and teached in 4 universities in France and Austria. Currently, I am a technical leader at *Altran* in Toulouse. I supervise developers for client projects on Model Based Software Engineering and Agile Frameworks, participate in R&D projects, supervise interns, lead answers to RfQs and conceive and provide software trainings.

Skills ———

Model Based Software Engineering

Java

Eclipse EMF, RCP

Shell

Agile frameworks

Project Management

Languages -

French, English, Arabic, Kabyle, German (beginner)

Interests —

African History and Post-crossing.

Experience

since 2019 Software Technical Leader Altran Technologies

I supervise developers for software projects for clients such as Airbus. I participate to RFQ answers and provide trainings on Model-Based

Software Engineering.

2018 Researcher & Teacher Technische Universität Wien

I was conducting research on Model Driven Engineering and I gave

courses on Graphical Modelling in English

2016-2018 Researcher & Teacher Universite de Nantes

I was responsible of students groups for many computer science courses: programming, databases, web programming and I con-

ducted researches on Model Driven Engineering

2013-2016 Young Researcher Universite de Montpellier

I was preparing my PhD in computer science in *Lirmm* research lab and teaching computer science courses in the *Faculty of Sciences*

Education

2013-2016 Ph.D. candidate in Computer Science Universite de Montpellier

A Declarative Approach for Model Generation

2012-2013 Master in Computer Science Universite de Montpellier

Specializing in Software Engineering

2011-2013 Master in Computer Science Universite de Bejaia

Specializing in Networks and Distributed Systems

2008-2011 Bachelor Universite de Bejaia

Specializing in mathematics and informatics.

Notable Facts

Publications 10 papers in journal, international conferences or workshops

Best Paper ICSEA 2017, Athens, Greece

Talks Montpellier, Nantes, Lille, Angers, Paris, Bordeaux, Washington DC,

San Francisco, Oslo, Copenhagen, Athens & Vienna.

Teaching +800 hours teaching in 4 universities, +10 different topics and train-

inas for engineers.

Industrials Airbus, Dassault, Safran Certification Professional Scrum Master I



Previous & Current Projects

HQ Workbe. Architect & Scrum Master Airbus

Digital Transformation of HQ Data and Tools

IPad Technical Leader Airbus

A workbench for aerodynamics studies

Icing Technical Leader & Developer Airbus

A Workbench for Icing Tools & Data

Optimind R&D Project Leader Altran Research

A Model-Driven toolbox for engineers

Rumor Developer Airbus

Automate and migrate simulation tools

Grimm Architect & Developer Lirmm

Automatic Model Generator